### **Austin Carey**

### **SUMMARY**

Conscientious individual with 10+ years of experience leveraging technical capabilities and subject matter expertise to analyze data to inform policy and drive business decisions. I also serve my country part time as a Military Officer and Pilot.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Data Analysis & Visualization | Stakeholder Relations | Project Management | Technical Reports | Aviation | Leadership

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Analyst | Salt River Project | Oct 2023 – Present Data Analyst | Salt River Project | Oct 2022 – Oct 2023

- Develop business intelligence dashboards integrating SQL Server dbs and REST APIs to guide operational decisions (over ten dashboards ranked in the top 1% of usage within a 5,000+ person organization)
- Optimize business processes (data entry, analysis, reporting, etc.) by writing R and Python scripts
- Maintain and QA/QC database of record for all water resource datasets within the organization
- Project manager for multi-year study to evaluate snow instrumentation

Pilot | Missouri Air National Guard | Dec 2023 - Present

Rated Pilot and 2nd Lieutenant

Data Analyst II | Central Arizona Project | Aug 2018 - Oct 2022

- Served as lead GoldSim modeler and project manager for three multiyear, regional scale assessments to forecast and evaluate water supply and demand over a 40-year horizon for Phoenix and Tucson areas
- Analyzed water operations data using SQL and analytical tools to inform state and federal water policy decisions
- Technical liaison between the organization and external stakeholders
- Distilled data analysis results into digestible and actionable items for senior management and board members

Renewable Energy Consultant | CORE Energy Group | Sep – Dec 2021

- Built strategic relationships with clients to assist them with solar energy solutions
- Awarded top sales representative for the company in Q3 of CY21

**Technician** | Hudbay Minerals | Jan – Aug 2017

- Developed a water quality assurance plan for proposed mine site
- Managed local and cloud-based geodatabases of instrumentation

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

TS/SCI Clearance (Tier 5) | Federal Government | Jan 2024 Certificate of Leadership & Communication | Harvard X | Oct 2022 Certificate of Business w/ Management Emphasis | Pima CC | May 2018



**(**307) 223 - 6035

✓ austinmartincarey@gmail.com

in LinkedIn

Google Scholar (Publications)

Website Website

### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science – Hydrology & Water Resources

University of Wyoming, 2016 Awarded Outstanding Masters Student (1 of 3,000 students)

# Bachelor of Science – Watershed Hydrology & Management

University of Arizona, 2013 Awarded Outstanding Graduating Senior (1 of 75 students)

### **SKILLS**

### **Professional**

Project Management | Stakeholder Relations | Professional Presentations | Sales Experience | Verbal and Written Communication | Leadership

### **Technical**

Data Acquisition & Organization | Data Analysis & Visualization | Database Management | Microsoft Office and Google Suite | Statistical Analysis

### **Software & Programming**

R & R Studio | Plotly | Shiny | Power BI Tableau | SQL | VBA | Python | REST APIs | HTML\* | GoldSim | ArcPro | PgAdmin | Advanced MS Excel

\* Indicates beginner competency

### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

- Hydrologic Technician
  U.S. Geological Survey
- Researcher
  Smithsonian Tropical Research
  Institute
- Researcher
  USDA Ag. Research Service